RG 004:168, Woodbury Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Woodbury Probate Court records
1719-1949
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Woodbury District)
72.25 cubic feet
Record books, 1719-1944; Probate files, 1720-1949.
RG004_168
1915-026, 2011-104, T003295
Historical Note
Woodbury, Litchfield County, Town named May 1673
The Woodbury Probate District was constituted October 1719 from the Fairfield, Hartford and New Haven Probate Districts. It also served the following municipalities at various times: Bethlehem, May 1787 - January 4, 2011; New Milford, October 1719 - May 1787; Roxbury, October 1796 - June 4, 1842; Southbury, May 1787 - January 3, 1967; Washington, January 1770 - May 21, 1832 (covered Judea Society, i.e. the parts of town taken from Woodbury and New Milford). The Woodbury Probate District merged with the Oxford, Roxbury, Southbury, and Washington Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region # 22 Probate District which serves the municipalities of Bethlehem, Oxford, Roxbury, Southbury, Washington, Watertown, and Woodbury.
Town of Woodbury, Probate District chronology:
Before 1698, Colonial Jurisdiction
1698 - October 1719 Fairfield District
October 1719 - January 4, 2011, Woodbury District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region # 22 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, vol. 1-57, 1719-1944. There is also a supplement to volume 3, an index to volume 1, and index to volumes 2-3, and a typed index covering circa 1719-1860. Contact the probate court to access original record books numbered after 57. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1720-1949, Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1720-1943 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2011-104 are numbered 1-57. There are two volumes numbered 3.
Probate files in accessions 1915-026 and T003295 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1915-026 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Bethlehem; Probate records -- Connecticut -- New Milford; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Roxbury; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Southbury; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Washington; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Woodbury
Places:
Bethlehem (Conn.); New Milford (Conn.); Roxbury (Conn.); Southbury (Conn.); Washington(Conn.); Woodbury (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-104, Record books, 1719-1944, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files from 1921-1946 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, vol. 1-23, 25-28, 30, 32, 34, 36, 38, 40, 42-43, 46-47, 49-50, 52-54, 56, 1719-1916; probate files, 1720-1880; and inventory control book were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1915-026 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): September 9, 1915 (1720-1910); July 8, 1941 (1873-1922); September 9, 1942 (1749-1943); March 23, 1943 (1749-1943); September 24, 1943 (1749-1943); June 14, 1944 (1749-1943). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
It is not known when the probate files in accession T003295 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library.
The record books in accession 2011-104 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 20, 2011.
Container List
- Record books, 1719-1944; 24 cubic feet (60 volumes + 1 item); 2011-104
  - Index covering circa 1718-1860, 1 item (Volume unnumbered)
  - Index vol 1 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Index vol 2,3 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Records, 1719-1933 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1733-1748 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1749-1754 (Volume 3)
  - Records, supplement, 1754-1760 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1757-1760 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1760-1766, 1772, 1783, 1785 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1766-1773, 1785 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1773-1778, 1786, 1787 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1779-1786 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1786-1798 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1798-1814 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1807-1816 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1813-1818 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1820-1825 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1824-1829 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1826-1830 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1828-1833 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1731-1838 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1835-1843 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1840-1843 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1843-1849 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1849-1858 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1856-1862 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1862-1865 (Volume 23)
  - Orders and decrees, 1864-1872 (Volume 24)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1865-1869 (Volume 25)
  - Guardians, 1824-1866 (Volume 26)
  - Guardians, 1866-1900 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1869-1874 (Volume 28)
  - Orders and decrees, 1872-1877 (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1874-1877 (Volume 30)
  - Orders and decrees, 1877-1880 (Volume 31)
  - Records, 1874-1880 (Volume 32)
  - Orders nad decrees, 1880-1884 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1880-1883 (Volume 34)
  - Bonds, 1881-1896 (Volume 35)
  - Records, 1883-1887 (Volume 36)
  - Orders and decrees, 1884-1887 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1887-1889 (Volume 38)
  - Orders and decrees, 1887-1892 (Volume 39)
  - Records, 1890-1892 (Volume 40)
  - Orders and decrees, 1892-1896 (Volume 41)
  - Records, 1890-1894 (Volume 42)
  - Records, 1894-1896 (Volume 43)
  - Bonds, 1896-1922 (Volume 44)
  - Orders and decrees, 1896-1901 (Volume 45)
    on spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1897-1900 (Volume 46)
  - Records, 1899-1902 (Volume 47)
  - Orders and decrees, 1901-1906 (Volume 48)
  - Records, 1902-1905 (Volume 49)
  - Records, 1904-1909 (Volume 50)
  - Orders and decrees, 1907 (Volume 51)
  - Records, 1908-1910 (Volume 52)
  - Records, 1910-1915 (Volume 53)
  - Records, 1912-1913 (Volume 54)
  - Orders and decrees, 1914, 1941-1944 (Volume 55)
  - Records, 1912-1917 (Volume 56)
  - Records, 1916-1923 (Volume 57)
- Probate files, 1720-1943; 36.25 cubic feet; 1915-026
  - A - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 1-109)
- Inventory Control Book, 1720-1943; T003073
  Index of the six accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1915-026
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, circa 1910-1949; 12 cubic feet; T003295
  There is no index for this accession.
  - Abraham - Ames (Box 1)
  - Anderson - Ayres (Box 2)
  - Baron - Baldwin, D. (Box 3)
  - Baldwin, E. - Bell (Box 4)
  - Benedict - Brown (Box 5)
  - Brundage - Cam (Box 6)
  - Candee - Champoli (Box 7)
  - Churchill - Curtis (Box 8)
  - Dakin - Dayton (Box 9)
  - Dearborn - Evans (Box 10)
  - Eyre - Fortt (Box 11)
  - Fowler - Griswold (Box 12)
  - Gruber - Hawley (Box 13)
  - Hayes - Hirsch (Box 14)
  - Hitchcock - Huntington (Box 15)
  - Isham - Keil (Box 16)
  - Kenway - Larson (Box 17)
  - Le Comte - Magee (Box 18)
  - Maier - Marvin (Box 19)
  - Mazaika - Morris (Box 20)
  - Mosevege - Norton (Box 21)
  - O'Brien - Peck (Box 22)
  - Percy - Pinkerton (Box 23)
  - Platt - Quick (Box 24)
  - Rainey - Richards (Box 25)
  - Robinson - St. Pierre (Box 26)
  - Salmon - Senkus (Box 27)
  - Shea - Steiglitz (Box 28)
  - Stiles - Sturges (Box 29)
  - Sullivan - Thompson (Box 30)
  - Thomson - Tomlinson (Box 31)
  - Traub - Urbaties (Box 32)
  - Valentini - Ward (Box 33)
  - Warner - Werner (Box 34)
  - Wheeler - Wood (Box 35)
  - Woodward - Zepp; & Probate Index Lists (Box 36)